# **BAVELY TAWFIK**

Fountain Valley, CA

Phone: (626) 626-5854 | Email: <u>bavlesamy@gmail.com</u> | LinkedIn: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/bavelytawfik</u> Portfolio: <u>https://pavli-tawfik.com</u> | GitHub: <u>https://github.com/bavely</u> | <u>https://github.com/PavliTawfik</u>

# **Summary**

Motivated full-stack web developer with extensive knowledge of web development, design, and coding in addition to experience in a wide range of programming languages, frameworks, and tools. Proven success in developing and deploying applications, websites, and web services. Highly organized and detail-oriented, with a knack for finding creative solutions to challenging problems.

#### Skills

#### **Technical Skills**

JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Node.js, Microservices, NPM, PHP, C#, .NET, jQuery, Angular, ReactJs, NextJs, Redux, Redux tool-kit, React Native, CSS, UI/UX, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, JSON, AJAX, HTML / HTML5, OpenAl API, APIs, GraphQL, Nexus WordPress, version control systems (Git), Cloud Hosting (Google Cloud and MS Azure), Google Firebase services, Google domains and G Suite, Al & ML, CI/CD, Twilio API, MySQL, MS SQL Server, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Prisma ORM, Windows Server 2008, 2012, 2016, Active Directory, DNS, DHCP, LAN, WAN, VoIP, Firewalls implementation and administration.

### **Soft Skills**

Strong problem-solving abilities, Excellent team collaboration, Attention to Detail, Passion for exploring innovative methods and Proficient in help desk support.

# **Experience**

#### WEB DEVELOPER

### **NEXTEHEALTH, LLC IN IRVINE, CA (REMOTE)**

#### FROM JANUARY 2022 TO PRESENT

- Building the front end of a web-based pharmacy application using ReactJs and other JavaScript libraries.
- · Cooperating in building the same application's back-end with NodeJs, ExpressJs, Microservices and database schema.
- Participating in planning each milestone and organizing the work.

#### FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

# AT&T IN DURHAM, NC (REMOTE)

#### FROM JULY 2021 TO JANUARY 2022

- · Upgraded the jQuery version of one of the main operational software in the company.
- · Built customized reusable functions to replace the deprecated methods of older jQuery versions.
- Evaluated and performed code reviews for other developers' code changes.
- Performed quality assurance tests of the application beta releases.

# SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR II / WEB DEVELOPER RIVER'S EDGE PHARMACY IN IRVINE, CA

#### FROM FEBRUARY 2018 TO JULY 2021

• Built company operational web app "CliniVoy.com" using NodeJs , Angular, MS SQL Server, Google Firebase services (Auth & real-timeDB) , and Google Cloud as hosting environment and domain provider.

- · Managed the technical operations and maintenance of the company's main website "repharmacy.com".
- Planned and executed the migration of on-premises servers to Azure Cloud VMs.
- Installed, configured, and deployed multiple MS SQL servers including creating new databases, and tables, and building reusable queries.
- · Managed Azure services including but not limited to Azure virtual machines, WordPress web apps service by Azure, Azure DNS, and VPN Gateway.
- · Managed and supervised Azure services including but not limited to Azure virtual machines, WordPress web apps service by Azure, Azure DNS, and VPN Gateway.

#### WEB DEVELOPER

#### GLOBAL NET SOLUTIONS IN TORRANCE, CA

#### FROM DECEMBER 2017 TO FEBRUARY 2018

- · Installed, configured, and deployed WordPress platform website on-site ground web host.
- · Developed and deployed the corporate website using WordPress.
- · Designed web applications using MERN technology, which includes MongoDB, ExpressJs, ReactJs, and NodeJS.

# ELECTRONICS ENGINEER RAYA COMPANY IN CAIRO, EGYPT

#### FROM NOVEMBER 2015 TO JULY 2016

- · Resolved smartphone hardware and software issues.
- Managed face-to-face customer complaints effectively while serving as a manager's assistant, achieving exceptionally high customer satisfaction based on feedback surveys. This success contributed to a notable increase in the branch's revenue of 27% within a month.

#### **ELECTRICAL ENGINEER**

## EGYPTIAN SWISS CO. IN 10TH OF RAMADAN CITY, EGYPT

#### FROM AUGUST 2012 TO AUGUST 2014

- · Solved production line alarms quickly, which is incorporated into increasing productivity by 30%.
- · Created a periodic maintenance plan that allowed the maintenance team to regularly check all machines and electrical panels, reducing the number of critical issues by almost 25%.

# COMMUNICATION ENGINEER

#### **MOBISERVE CAIRO, EGYPT**

#### FROM SEPTEMBER 2011 TO SEPTEMBER 2012

- Successfully provided solutions for repeated issues, which translated to time and money savings for the company and incorporated into increasing the network efficiency of the assigned area by 20%.
- Performed periodic and emergency maintenance, surpassed on time and efficiently with satisfactory results from the company by managing a team of 5 technicians.

## Education

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING | MAY 2011 | EL-SHOROUK ACADEMY - THE HIGHER INSTITUTE OF ENGINEERING, EL-SHOROUK CITY, EGYPT.

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM | SEPTEMBER 2017 | UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA - THE DIVISION OF CONTINUING EDUCATION, IRVINE, CALIFORNIA.